# Patrick M. Dunn

E-mail: pmdunn78@gmail.com || Phone: +1 (860) 921-3424 || New Hartford, CT 06057

Portfolio: https://knightmac19.github.io/R-profile/

Github: https://github.com/knightmac19/ || LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/patrick-dunn-3a14249b

#### **SUMMARY**

Full Stack Web Developer and bilingual carpenter with international teaching experience. Learned the MERN stack while earning a Full Stack Web Certificate from the University of Connecticut. Studied Spanish and German at Wheaton College (IL), later earning a TEFL Certificate which allowed me to teach English in Mexico for a year. Driven to design and build elegantly structured web applications, applying my love of simple and profound functionality from my building experience.

#### **PROJECTS**

## **Matrixio**

MERN Stack application that allows speech language pathologists to create matrix exercises for their students. My Role: writing server routes to connect user input in the database & maintaining application state in React. https://github.com/pipetro/Matrixio/

https://serene-river-18393.herokuapp.com/

## **Employee Directory**

React project that returns employee data from an API and continuously filters the results as the user searches across multiple categories (name, DOB, phone, etc.).

https://github.com/knightmac19/employee-directory-pmd/

https://knightmac19.github.io/employee-directory-pmd/

## **Crime Stats**

Project combining FBI data and Mapbox to show relative crime bubbles across the 50 states from 2000-2018. https://github.com/knightmac19/CrimeStats/

https://knightmac19.github.io/CrimeStats/

## LANGUAGES / TECHNOLOGIES

•	ReactJS	•	Express	•	NodeJS	•	CSS
•	MongoDB / Mongoose	•	jQuery	•	Git	•	HTML
•	Twitter Bootstrap	•	Heroku	•	MVC App Structure	•	mySQL

## **EDUCATION**

UCONN Coding Bootcamp, Hartford, CT (Programming Certificate)	2019 - 2020
International TEFL Academy, Chicago, IL (TEFL Certificate)	2018
Wheaton College, Wheaton, IL (B.S. in Spanish)	2013 - 2016
Study Abroad, Santiago de Querétaro, México	Spring 2014

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Freelance English Teacher

2018 - 2019

Applied TEFL certificate by teaching English in Mexico. Gave private lessons as well as classes in various factories for management teams.

## ZN Construction, Canton, CT

2016 - 2018

Journeyman Carpenter specializing in trim and molding. Rapidly given increasing responsibility, including the lead on small projects.

## Doot Construction, Torrington, CT

2011 – 2016, 2019 – Present

Apprentice Carpenter with broad responsibilities. Received regular pay increases and additional responsibility.

## Hartford Family Medicine

Summer 2015

Assessed and routed patient phone calls, managed provider schedules, and processed patient records in bilingual (Spanish / English) family medical office.

#### TRAVEL / INTERNATIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Santiago de Querétaro, Mexico

2018 - 2019

Summer 2016

Taught English for a year in Mexico's historic heartland.

Western Europe

Backpacked through France, Switzerland, and Germany.

Honduras Spring 2015

Team member of initiative that brought running water to two remote mountain villages.

## Santiago de Querétaro, Mexico

Spring 2014

Lived with a host family for a semester in Mexico's historic heartland.

#### **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

# ESL class, Valley Community Baptist Church, Avon, CT

2017 - 2019

Volunteer instructor at a weekly ESL (English as a Second Language) class. Led activities emphasizing student engagement and fostering original language creation.

#### Honduras Project, Wheaton, IL

2014 - 2015

Raised money for potable water systems for two Honduran villages through yard work and donations over the course of the  $^{14}-^{15}$  academic year.

#### Tutoring, Hartford City Mission, Hartford, CT

2011 - 2012

Volunteer tutor during high school for an after-school program in Hartford. Helped elementary-age children with their homework, reading, and recreational activities.

#### INTERESTS / OTHER SKILLS

- German (A2 Level)
- 2014 Chicago Marathon
- Wheaton Club Soccer

- Portuguese (A2 Level)
- CT All-State HS Soccer
- Brazilian Jiu Jitsu

- Brazilian Jiu Jitsu
- HS Soccer Co-Captain